Tareq Aghabi

+971 52 522 9094 | tareqaghabi@gmail.com | Linkedin

PROFILE

Senior Data Analyst and Industrial Engineer with 4+ years of experience in Supply Chain Analytics, Big Data Operations, and Tech Logistics. Proficient in SQL, Python, R, LookML, Tableau, Power BI, JavaScript, Google Apps Script, ERP Dynamics 365, Excel, HTML, and CSS. Canadian and Jordanian citizen, native in English and Arabic.

EDUCATION

IBM, School of Data Science

IBM

Professional Certificate in Data Science

May 2021

Relevant Coursework: SQL, Python, Data Analysis, Visualization, ETL, Development, Machine Learning

Harvard University, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences

HarvardX

Professional Certificate in Data Science

February 2021

Relevant Coursework: R, Visualization, Probability, Modeling, Wrangling, Regression, Machine Learning & AI

Concordia University, School of Engineering and Computer Science

Montréal, QC

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering (BEng)

May 2019

• Relevant Coursework: Operations Research, Stochastic Models, Simulation, Calculus, Probability & Statistics

Amman Baccalaureate School, Applied Sciences

Amman, JOD

International Baccalaureate Diploma Program (IBDP)

May 2014

• Relevant Coursework: Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chalhoub Group – Luxury goods retailer and distributor

Dubai, UAE

Data Analyst II - Supply Chain - Managed Companies Demand & Supply Analytics

January 2022 - Present

- Utilized Python and R to build and implement an automated store-to-store inventory allocation & replenishment model using time series forecasts customized on 25+ luxury retails brands, which reduced 20+ hours per brand in manual weekly inventory rotations and generated an additional \$30 million in sales.
- Scraped and wrangled 10TB of stock on hand and historical sales data from Looker to generate hierarchal forecasts to
 calculate safety stock on a store-item level, and then rotated stock between stores based on safety stock and stock cover,
 optimizing 50000+ item location replenishments weekly per brand and country.
- Drove the Group's upstream and downstream Supply Chain strategic direction by establishing corporate level reporting on stock cover, in stock rate, stock on hand and fill rate using Looker visualizations, delivering actionable insights influencing key business decision-making and empowering stakeholders.

<u>Goodfood Market Corporation</u> – Canadian online grocery delivery

Montréal, QC

Operations Analyst – Big Data Analytics & Digital Operations

April 2021 – January 2022

- Promoted to Operations Analyst within an eight-month timeframe for exceeding goals and supporting company culture.
- Configured the weekly system changeover for over 1500 new SKU items in the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system, determining multi-facility SKU picking & storage locations and inventory replenishment triggers based on analysis of order volume projections and operations cost analysis.
- Automated customer order data pull schedules from Looker into Google Sheets to develop an interfacility inventory replenishment analysis model using JavaScript, improving item replenishment availability and visibility by 50%.
- Strategically assigned over 3000 multi-facility SKU storage and picking locations data into the Goodfood E-commerce backend database and ERP warehouse management system using Microsoft SQL Server Studio queries.
- Created over 10 automated analysis tools and visualization dashboards for logging short ship data, managing labor cost, and tracking shipping carrier progress, informing daily item management decisions to senior directors and executives.

Production Supervisor – Supply Chain Operations

August 2020 – April 2021

- Utilized Excel to implement data cross-validation for recipe batch production requirements on 600+ batches, which reduced total production errors by 95%.
- Wrangled multiple recipe production datasets stored in Google Data Studio using Excel pivot tables to remodel and visualize datasets to allow operations and senior management to track the location and status of recipe batch production.
- Actively supervised workflow, delegated strategy and trained production and inventory teams of over 25 associates to maintain operational efficiency, increasing overall recipe pallet building productivity by 20%.

<u>United Parcel Service</u> (UPS) – Global shipping & logistics

Montréal, QC

 $Industrial\ Engineering\ Specialist-Route\ Optimization\ Engineering\ Project\ Team$

April 2019 - May 2020

- Utilized UPS mapping and optimization software to plot and schedule delivery route information for over 70 training and verification rides on deployed driver groups, decreasing route delivery mileage by 15%.
- Extracted and manipulated route-specific statistics stored in UPS proprietary databases using Excel Visual Basic to generate over 25 technical reports, providing corporate-wide visibility to overall project deployment progress.
- Optimized and scheduled over 1800 driver and helper meetups in all regions of Montréal and Laval using UPS logistics software, resulting in an increase of 70 stops per package-car during peak season.
- Created a Master Operating Plan on the Data Acquisition department documenting the data collection and transformation methods for package processing at UPS, standardizing data processing operations and decreasing errors by 25%.